



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior UX Designer | USAA | May 2021-Present

- Leads AEM Design System team through the creation and release of new components, design guidance and documentation, and process refinement
- · Applies advanced knowledge and experience in the practice of human-centered design.
- Synthesizes the work of cross functional teams to deliver a unified design vision for complex Member and Employee experiences in a data-informed, agile environment.
- Demonstrates the value of design by building trust-based relationships that influence the alignment of stakeholders across projects, teams, and functions.

Senior UX Designer/Consultant | Slalom | April 2019-May 2021

- · Lead projects in user-centered design solutions using Design Thinking methodologies
- · Work with development teams and project leadership to define and refine scope
- Produce wireframes, user flows, IA diagrams and prototypes for web and mobile experiences, manage design assets, and review UI for proper implementation

Lead UX/UI Designer | ConversionPoint Technologies | December 2017 - April 2019

- · Researched and managed projects, providing leadership and direction
- · Began research and initial development of new design system
- · Collaborated with cross-functional team to create solutions that stressed empathy to the user, strived for accessibility, and maintained attention to detail

Front-end Developer | The Lacek Group | December 2010 - May 2011

- Created microsites, single page sites, and HTML emails for clients such as American Airlines and Enterprise Rent-A-Car with a cohesive interactive design team
- Worked extensively with testing software (Litmus) to provide support for a multitude of email clients

Graphic Design Internship | Booz Allen Hamilton | June 2007 - December 2007

· Worked with internal stakeholders to provide print and digital design deliverables

Sergeant | Wisconsin Army National Guard | August 1998 - August 2008

- · Ultimately worked in a leadership role (88M, 92A) as part of several units
- Served year-long tour in Operation Iraqi Freedom in support role transporting equipment and personnel from various locations in Iraq back to base in Kuwait

ABOUT ME

I currently lead USAA's AEM Design System team with the goal of building better experiences for our military members and their families.

Home is Minneapolis where I enjoy hiking with my wife and pets, video games, books, and movies.

SKILLSET

- · Project/Client Consultation
- · Design Thinking
- · Usability Testing
- · User Experience Design
- · Information Architecture
- · Responsive Website Design
- Front-end (HTML/CSS/JS)
- · Strive for Accessibility
- · Browser/Device Testing
- · Prototypes

SOME TOOLS I USE

- · Miro
- · Balsamiq
- Figma
- Sketch
- InVision
- · Adobe Creative Suite
- · Sublime Text
- · CodeKit
- · BrowserStack
- · Zeplin
- Hotjar

EDUCATION

Winona State University

BA in Graphic Design w/minor in Marketing

MILITARY ACHIEVEMENTS

- · Commandant's Honor List
- · Army Achievement Medal
- · Overseas Service Ribbon